Aki Sirkiä

Curriculum Vitae

Email: aki.sirkia@gmail.com

Phone: +358400929411

GitHub: Aki Sirkiä

Personal Statement

As a third-year student pursuing a bachelor's degree in Computer Science at Kristianstad University, I have developed a strong foundation in programming concepts and technologies. In addition to my coursework, I have also taken online courses on data structures, algorithms, and design patterns on codewithmosh.com. Although I do not have professional experience in programming, I have been a teacher's aide for a data structures and algorithms course and have a personal project on GitHub that focused on the backend part of coding puzzles for students. I am particularly interested in testing and security and my thesis project is focused on pseudorandomness from user input using an Android device.

Education

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science, Kristianstad University (Expected Graduation Date: 06 2023) GPA: 3.88 (out of 4.0).

Thesis Project

Exploring Hardware-Based Randomness Generation on Android Devices: A Comparative Analysis.

Work Experience

| Teacher's Assistant, Kristianstad University 2022 – 2023 | Assisted with data structures and algorithms course. Held office hours and helped students with assignments. Had a lecture about design patterns, and held help sessions. |
|---|---|
| Professional Billiards Player 2016 - 2019 | Developed dedication, self-improvement, focus, and independent responsibility skills. |
| Conductor, Finnish Railway 2012 - 2016 | Worked as part of a team with high demands for independence and teamwork. Promoted initiative when situations changed rapidly. Designated as the lead conductor in multiple train runs. |

Security Officer, Private Security Industry 2006 - 2014 Performed diverse tasks ranging from basic fieldwork to external security audits and surveillance operations. Trained and licensed to handle special equipment and difficult situations. Handled high-stress situations and tasks with quick adaptation skills. Occasionally designated as lead responsibility for spontaneous events.

Software Development Experience:

- Knowledge of Agile development methodologies and experience working in Agile teams
- Proficient in multiple programming languages including Python, Typescript, JavaScript, Java, and Kotlin
- Experienced in developing web applications using Angular, HTML, CSS, Node.js,
 Express.js, and Django
- Experienced in android development with android studio and Kotlin.
- Familiar with databases such as MySQL and MongoDB
- Skilled in big data technologies like Hadoop and Spark
- Familiar with version control systems such as Git
- Experience working on both Windows and Linux operating systems.
- Knowledge of machine learning libraries such as scikit-learn.

References

Available upon request.